原作者名：I Need More Space
视频来源：youtu.be/t1tsU3Se6GM
原视频发布日期：20200710
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
- Hey everybody, TJ here from "I Need More Space".
- 嘿 大家好 我是TJ  欢迎观看 I Need More Space
I typically don't do these like news videos
我通常不做这些像新闻视频一样的东西
but I felt like this was something that we should really talk about.
但我觉得这是我们应该好好讨论的事情
This week, NASA and Boeing completed their test review
本周 NASA和波音公司完成了他们的测试审查
from the botched Boeing Starliner launch a few months ago back in December 2019.
从几个月前 早在2019年12月的波音星际客机发射的失误
Something that we all kind of knew was
我们大概知道的事情是
that Boeing was always kinda the favorite child in the Commercial Crew Program between Boeing and SpaceX,
在商业载人计划中 相比SpaceX 波音是那个被偏爱的孩子
where Boeing got more funding and frankly,
波音从这个计划中得到了更多的资金
just some more leeway in their program.
坦率地说 只是让他们的计划中多了一些冗余
SpaceX was just looked at under a microscope but we never had anything official until now.
SpaceX则被严格审查 但直到现在我们才有了正式的消息
NASA essentially admits that they gave Boeing a very long leash during this process
NASA基本上承认 在这个过程中 他们过于宽容波音
and trusted them because of their history with the space shuttle and the International Space Station
并信任他们 因为他们与航天飞机和国际空间站的历史
and other cost-plus contracts that they worked on,
以及他们所从事的其他成本加成合同(上的表现)
Space Launch System included.
包括太空发射系统
Now, I can go into this in a lot of detail
现在 我可以详细介绍一下这个问题
but I figured I'd let the NASA spokespeople just talk for themselves.
但我想我会让NASA的发言人为自己说话
This was initially a one hour long phone call that I decided to cut down to the most important aspects.
这是最初的一个小时长的电话 我决定削减到最重要的方面
Kathy Lueders之前担任NASA商业载人计划项目经理
The two NASA spokespeople that you hear today is Kathy Lueders,
今天你听到的两位NASA发言人是Kathy Lueders
前任载人探索与行动任务局局长Douglas Loverro于2020年5月18日辞职
who's the Associate Administrative of Human Exploration and Operations Mission Directorate,
她是载人探索与行动任务局的副局长
congratulations on your promotion,
恭喜你升职
and Steve Stich, the Commercial Crew Program Manager.
和Steve Stich 商业载人计划项目经理
So they are the folks that really oversaw this review and are falling on the sword, so to speak.
所以他们才是真正监督这次审查的人 可以说是当事人
So let's just have a listen.
所以 让我们来听一听
- [Steve] It's great to be here today to continue to talk about our progress
- [Steve]很高兴今天能在这里继续讨论我们的进展情况
as we work toward the OFT-2 mission with our Boeing provider.
在我们与波音公司合作完成OFT -2任务的过程中
When we talked last to you in the March timeframe,
当我们上次与你谈话 在三月那时
at the time they had come up with 61 recommendations which we were in the process of reviewing,
当时他们提出了61项建议 我们正在审查这些建议
but since that time those really dealt with the two primary anomalies on the flight,
但自那以后 才真正处理了飞行中的两个主要异常现象
the liftoff time anomaly with the Starliner grabbing that time from the Atlas vehicle
升空时星际客机从宇宙神5火箭上对时的异常
and also the separation associated with the independent propulsion controller at the end of the flight.
以及飞行结束时与独立推进控制器相关的分离
Since then,
自此以后
we've implemented a number of other recommendations dealing with the communications anomalies,
我们已经执行了其他的许多建议 来处理通信异常的情况
www.nasa.gov/feature/nasa-and-boeing-complete-orbital-flight-test-reviews
and now we're up to a total of 80 recommendations that you'll see on the blog post.
而现在我们一共有80个建议 你会在文章里看到
We had the team interviewed about a total of 20 plus people across NASA and Boeing
我们的团队采访了NASA和波音公司总计20多个人
to try to better understand other causes
来更好地了解除此之外的其他原因
that could have led to the anomalies that we saw on the OFT mission back in December.
那些原因导致的我们在12月OFT任务中看到了异常情况
So that report is closed out.
所以 这个报告是结束了
Some of the things we looked at was did we have the right level of engagement from the beginning,
我们要研究的是 我们从一开始(对这件事)是否有适当的参与程度
and I'll remind people that the commercial model that we're utilizing
我要提醒大家的是 目前我们使用的这种商业模型
has shared accountability between NASA and the contractor.
NASA和承包商之间的都负有责任
When we went back and looked back at our culture
当我们回过头来看我们的文化时
and the way we were approaching software development with Boeing,
以及我们与波音公司进行软件开发的方式
perhaps we didn't have as many people as embedded in that process as we should have.
也许我们没有那么多的人参与到这个过程中来 而我们不应该这么做
- [Kathy] Whenever you go to one of these things
- [Kathy]每当你去参加这些活动的时候
it's a real huge learning opportunity for us then to look at our other processes with a new lens
对我们来说 这是一个真正的巨大学习机会 然后用新的视角来审视我们的其他流程
and just make sure that we're able to not only find the initial error,
而只要确保我们不仅能够找到最初的错误
but also that we have ways through our testing and assessment programs
但也能有办法通过我们的测试和评估计划
to be able to catch the errors at the right time.
以便能够在正确的时间发现错误
Boeing also is changing how they're doing business to you.
波音公司也在改变他们对你的业务方式
Right, I think this is a place
对 我认为在这一点上
where both Boeing and NASA we're learning together about doing business in this new way.
波音和NASA正一起学习以这种新的方式开展业务
This is a different model than having a cost-plus contract with Boeing,
这与波音公司签订的成本加成合同是不同的模式
and I think that's gonna be real learning that we can take forward into our Human Lander System Program.
我认为这将是真正的学习 可将其带入到我们的载人(登月)着陆器系统项目中
- [Steve] We tend to try to ask ourselves all the time when we're working with both partners,
- [Steve]当我们和两个合作伙伴一起工作时 我们会经常问自己
are we looking at the higher risk systems on each vehicle consistently?
我们是否在持续关注每个航天器上那些高风险的系统？
Across the board on each mission I think we've done a really good job at looking at all the higher risk areas
在每个任务中 我认为我们已经做得很好了 在所有高风险领域都有研究
and trying to focus on things that would be really detrimental if they happen in the flight.
并试图把注意力集中在那些如果在飞行中发将会非常糟糕的事情
I would say in the software area, from a NASA perspective,
我会说 从NASA的角度来看 在软件领域
we may have been focused a little more on SpaceX
我们可能更多关注的是SpaceX
because they use a bit of a non-traditional approach to their software development,
因为他们使用了一点非传统的软件开发方法
in terms of maybe a bit of a spiral development,
可能是有点螺旋式发展的情况
and then they code to the requirements
然后他们按照要求进行编程
and they do unit tests and they do all the kinds of typical software testing
他们做单元测试 他们做所有类型的典型软件测试
but they maybe do it in a, kind of a spiral development approach,
但他们也许会以一种 螺旋式发展的方式来做
which many aerospace companies do these days.
现在很多航空航天公司都这样做
And so we may have had a few more people looking at that.
所以可能有不少人在观察这种方式
And then we were, I would say, a little more used to the Boeing process.
然后我想说 我们更习惯于波音公司的流程
It's one that we have used in the past in successful NASA programs
这是我们过去在成功的NASA项目中使用过的一个流程
like Space Shuttle and the International Space Station,
比如航天飞机和和国际空间站
where you lay out all the requirements for the software,
在这里你列出了软件的所有需求
and then you hand them to the software team,
然后你再把它们交给软件团队
and then they implement those requirements.
然后他们实现这些需求
They test them at kind of a module level,
他们在模块层面进行测试
and then as they integrate modules, they test them.
然后当他们整合模块时 他们会对其进行(总的)测试
And so, perhaps we were a little more focused on SpaceX.
所以 可能我们对SpaceX的关注度更高一些
I think now looked back across both companies and tried to balance the portfolio of people we have,
我想现在回过头来看看这两家公司 并试图平衡我们的人员分配
we've certainly added resources to both software development on SpaceX and Boeing.
我们当然也为SpaceX和波音公司的软件开发增加了资源
These are complicated spacecraft with launching, landing,
这些都是涉及发射和着陆的复杂航天器
and then they do ascent aborts and they do aborts, as well, close to Space Station.
甚至还会进行发射中逃逸 靠近空间站 (等等)
So we've augmented resources on both partners to make sure that we're covered.
因此 我们在两个合作伙伴上增加了资源 以确保我们圆满地完成工作
When one provider has a newer approach than another,
当一个供应商比另一个供应商有更新的方法时
it's often natural for a human being to spend more time on that newer approach
人往往很自然地会花更多的时间在新的方法
and maybe we didn't quite take the time we needed with the more traditional approach.
也许对于这种更传统的方法 我们所使用的时间还不够
We had maybe more familiarity with the Boeing process
我们也许更熟悉波音公司的流程
from those that had worked on International Space Station.
对于那些曾在国际空间站工作的人
Many of the team that did the software for International Space Station was actually working on the Starliner
许多给国际空间站做软件的团队 实际上也给星际客机做软件
and so maybe we just didn't quite take the time that we needed to.
所以也许我们只是时间不够
In hindsight, these high visibility close calls and these investigations, you know, many times,
事后看来 这些引人注目的重大意外和相关调查 你知道 很多时候
I've seen it over my career, it's always,
我在我的职业生涯中见过这样的事情
it's a little more obvious afterwards than when you're in the middle of it.
相比在事情发生的过程中 (这些关注和调查)总是有点事后诸葛
And I think we've sort of learned that lesson,
我想我们已经差不多吸取了这个教训
and we're applying it equally across both providers.
而且这会在两个供应商之间平等地应用
We're looking to cross multiple systems on the vehicles
这将应用到航天器的多个系统上
whether it be the launch vehicle or the launchpad, the control center is to see if we have any other gaps.
无论是连着火箭 发射台 还是控制中心 在这些方面看看我们还有哪些漏洞
I think one of the things that these close calls do for you,
我认为这些重大意外的作用之一是
and Kathy talked about that for even Lander Systems,
Kathy也说到了 即便是对载人登月系统也有效
it's a bit of a wake-up call for NASA and its contractors,
可以说是给NASA和它的承包商敲响了警钟
and I would tell you all the contractors are,
我想告诉你所有的承包商都是
were interested when the anomalies happen.
都很关注异常情况的发生
IRT = Independent Review Team
When we had the IRT, they all want the lessons learned because they all know this business is really tough.
当我们有了独立审查团队时 他们都想吸取教训 因为他们都知道这一行真的很艰难
- [Kathy] This has been a big learning experience for us.
- [Kathy]这对我们来说是一个很大的学习经历
I tell people, and people get tired of hearing that and this was a gift,
我告诉人们 人们听腻了 说这是一份礼物
but this is helping us develop more robust processes across the Mission Directorate
但这正帮助我局建立一个更加健壮的(项目)处理流程
and then be able to provide that learning to the joint contractor NASA team.
然后让承包商和NASA都能从中学习
Perhaps to continue to apply these lessons to our further
也许能够继续将这些经验教训应用于我们的进一步发展过程中
and future success on the tough missions we have going forward.
并在未来的艰难任务中取得成功
- [Steve] When SpaceX had heard of the anomaly,
- 当SpaceX公司听说这个异常情况后
even after the OFT mission,
即使在OFT任务后
they began to contact us and ask questions about
他们开始与我们联系 询问关于
what, if anything, they could do to prevent this from happening on any of their flights.
如果有的话 他们可以做些什么来防止这种情况发生在他们的任何飞行中
And I think, in the aerospace industry,
我认为 在航空航天工业
all of the companies are sorta in it together and they all understand how tough it is,
所有的公司(遇到困难时)都差不多在一起 他们都明白这有多难
Axiom是和SpaceX合作搞国际空间站旅游的那家
and so all the companies, Sierra Nevada, Axiom, and others,
所以所有的公司 内华达山脉 Axiom等
are interested in learning from this particular anomaly.
都有兴趣从这个特殊的异常现象中学习
- So that's really it.
- 所以就是这样了
I could give NASA a lot of credit.
我可以好好夸夸NASA
It took a lot of guts for them to come out to the public and say,
他们花了很大的勇气来向公众宣布
"We tried our best but it wasn't enough." And I really hope that they learn from this.
我们已经尽力了 但还不够 我真的希望他们能从中吸取教训
I think it's only gonna make the Commercial Crew Program better.
我认为这只会让商业载人计划变得更好
I'd love to hear what y'all have to think in the comments below about this,
我很想听听你们在评论区的意见
and let's just hope for a brighter future with the Commercial Crew Program,
让我们希望商业载人计划有一个美好的未来
and that Boeing can just move on and have a great OFT, too.
而波音公司也可以继续前进 并且顺利完成在轨测试飞行
All right, thanks for watching.
好的 谢谢你的观看
Hope you learned something.
希望你能学到一些东西
Bye.
拜拜